Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp TAM.506
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp
2007-
TAM.506
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
0.0010 linear feet (1+ websites; i.e., a collection of websites that grows on an ongoing basis)
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Alternative Mass Media, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The Tamiment Library creates topically based archives of websites documenting labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States. The collection contains periodically archived websites of entities documenting (including via U.S. government websites), and of those entitie critical of U.S. policy and its representation governing enemy combatants, prisoner interrogation, the related legal processes and issues, the global detention system established by the Bush administration, including efforts to secure civil and human rights for detainees. Contents include prisoners' testimony and documents from attorneys defending them. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Note: if a link does not work, click on the TITLE of this archive (in the "Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access the archive, then go to the site list to access the web site(s) you wish to view.
Tamiment Library.
Scope and Contents note
This archive contains periodically archived websites of entities documenting (including via U.S. government websites) and of those critical of U.S. policy and its representation governing enemy combatants, prisoner interrogation, the related legal processes and issues, the global detention system established by the Bush administration, including efforts to secure civil and human rights for detainees. Contents include prisoners' testimony and documents from attorneys defending them. Also archived are the Guantanamo Reports and other documents created and published online by the Seton Hall University School of Law's Center for Social Justice, where faculty are creating a Guantanamo Bay Detention Center archive, to be housed at Seton Hall and at the Tamiment Library, NYU. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl.
Note: if a link does not work, click on the TITLE of this archive (in the "Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access the archive, then go to the site list to access the web site(s) you wish to view.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. This service employs open source web archiving utilities developed by Internet Archive with the support of the The International Internet Preservation Consortium. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The role of the Tamiment Library during this project and thereafter was/is to create topically based archives of websites documenting contemporary and ongoing labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
A list of related Tamiment Library web archives, whose ns2:titles all begin with the prefix "Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left), can be found at the website, Web Archives from New York University Libraries.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Related web archives, whose titles all begin with the prefix "Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left), include, but are not limited to archives pertaining to: Alternative Mass Media; Anarchism; Communism, Socialism, Trotskyism; the Jewish American Left; Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.); Prisoners Rights; Other Left Activism (from which additional topically based web archives will be periodically created).
Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp.; United States. Constitution. 8th Amendment.; Habeas corpus |z United States.; Iraq War, 2003- |x Prisoners and prisons, American; Prisoners of war |x Abuse of |z United States.; Torture |z United States.
- Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp Web Archive, 2007-
  - 100 Days to Close Guantánamo and End Torture, 07/06/2009-3/15/2010
  - Act Against Torture, 07/31/2009-2/8/2010
  - American Civil Liberties Union, Accountability for Torture, Restore the Rule of Law, Enhanced Interrogation Techniques, Waterboard, 07/30/2009-
  - American Civil Liberties Union, Close Gitmo & End Military Commissions, 07/31/2009-
  - American Civil Liberties Union, Safe and Free, 07/31/2009-
  - Camp Delta Standard Operating Procedure, 11/21/2007-7/11/2009
  - Center for Constitutional Rights Cases: Illegal Detentions and Guantanamo, 09/28/2009-
  - Combatant Status Review Tribunal (CSRT) and Administrative Review Board (ARB) Documents, 06/25/2009-
  - Crimes of War Project, 8/9/2010-
  - Detainee Death Investigation, 11/24/2009
  - Detainee Related Documents (United States. Dept. of Defense. Office of the Secretary of Defense and Joint Staff Reading Room), 06/26/2009
  - Detainees Positive Responses (pdf Object), 8/23/2009
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation-Guantanamo Bay Investigation, 11/30/2009
  - FOIA Post (2007): Summaries of New [Federal Court] Decisions-August 2007, 11/30/2009
  - FOIA Post (2009): Summaries of New [Federal Court] Decisions-January 2009, 11/20/2009
  - National Security Archive: The Torture Archive, 09/28/2009-
  - OIG Testimony-June 4, 2008, 11/30/2009-
  - OIG Testimony- June 10, 2008, 11/30/2009-
  - Reprieve, 6/1/2011-
  - Seton Hall Law School - Guantanamo Reports, 07/09/2009-
  - U.S. Department of Defense - Military Commissions, 07/28/2009-
  - U.S. Department of Defense - Military Commissions Brief Transcripts, 07/30/2009
  - U.S. Department of Defense - Military Commissions Combatant Status Review Tribunals, 07/06/2009
  - U.S. Dept. of Justice Office of the Inspector General Semiannual Report to Congress: April 1, 2008-September 30, 2008, 11/30/2009
  - U.S. Dept. of Justice Summaries of New Court Decisions - September 2009, 11/30/2009
  - U.S. Dept. of Justice Summaries of New [Federal Court] Decisions -- October 2008, 11/30/2009
  - U.S. Dept. of Justice: Summaries of New [Federal Court] Decisions -- June 2008, 11/30/2009
  - United States. Congress. Senate. Armed Services Committee. Inquiry into the treatment of detainees in U.S. custody, 11/20/2008, 09/28/2009
  - Witness against Torture: A Campaign to Shut down Guantanamo, 07/06/2009-